genieo.com 2018-12-26

# We care about your privacy | Genieo - A newspaper styled startpage

Genieo Innovation Ltd. (“ **Genieo Innovation** “) has a strong commitment to protect the privacy and the information of its users. Your privacy is very important to Genieo Innovation, and therefore, Genieo Innovation is committed to respect your privacy and the confidentiality of your information.  
This Privacy Policy statement aims to ensure the protection of your privacy, and also to assist you in understanding how Genieo Innovation treat your information while using Genieo Innovation’s softwares (including “Genieo”- hereinafter: “ **Genieo Software** “), services, website and/or products, as may be offered from time to time (collectively referred as “ **Services** ”). In addition, this Privacy Policy set forth Genieo Innovation’s privacy policy that is specific to Genieo Software.

**Acceptance of Policy**  
By accessing and using the Services, you agree to be bound by this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to any of the provisions as set hereunder in this Privacy Policy, you have no right to use any of the Services.  
If you intend to use Genieo Software, this Privacy Policy should read together with the End User License Agreement on Use of Genieo, and together they constitute the entire agreement between you and Genieo Innovation.

**Scope of This Privacy Policy Statement**  
This Privacy Policy describes how Genieo Innovation treat your information while you are using the Services. This Privacy Policy does not apply to any use of information by third parties’ linked sites or services, which Genieo Innovation does not control, own or manage, as further described in the “Disclaimer Regarding Linked Sites” paragraph below.

**Changes of the Privacy Policy**  
Genieo Innovation reserves the right to change this Privacy Policy at any time by publishing the revised Privacy Policy on Genieo Innovation’s website at [www.genieo.com](http://www.genieo.com/) and in case of a material change Genieo Innovation will also post a notification within the application. The revised Privacy Policy shall become effective within thirty (30) days of such publication. Your continued use of the Software after expiry of the notice period of thirty (30) days, shall constitute your acceptance to be bound by the terms and conditions of the revised Privacy Policy.

**Information Gathered Using the Services**  
The primary purpose of Genieo Innovation in collecting information is to provide you with a safe, efficient and customized experience. Accordingly, Genieo Innovation may collect non personal usage information of the users in order to ensure the quality of the Services and enrich the offerings of Services available to the users, and also to continuously improve the performance of the Services as described below.  
Genieo Innovation and its third party suppliers may collect, inter alia by using third parties’ web analytics services, aggregated non personal usage information about the time, type and manner of use of the Services (“ **Non Personal Usage Information** “). This Non Personal Usage Information may include information regarding the IP Address and Geo-IP parameters, time of usages, and other information regarding the use of the Services, including general categories of your areas of interest (such as sports, music, films and etc.). Such third parties’ web analytics services may use cookies and clear gifs to gather such Non Personal Usage Information, in order to learn the usage patterns of Genieo Innovation’s users (as further described below). Genieo Innovation may use Non Personal Usage Information to understand how its users use the Services, to analyze retention, to ensure that the Services is up to date and provide automatic updates of new version of Genieo Software, and to improve the Services and enhance the experience of the users.

In addition, Genieo Innovation and its third party suppliers may collect certain customary information from your use of the Services, including, inter alia, monitor your search engine queries and other information regarding the use of Genieo Innovation’s third party supplier’s search engine services. 

**Cookies and Clear Gifs Policy**  
As mentioned above, while Genieo Innovation uses third parties’ web analytics services as aforesaid, such third parties may collect Non Personal Usage Information, such as information concerning your use of websites and preferences, by using various types of cookies and clear gifs. Cookies, which are small text files, stored on your computer, in order to improve the performance of the Services and collect data which enhance the functionality and offering of the Services. Clear gifs are tiny graphics with a unique identifier (but not retain any personally identifiable information), which are used to count your visits/clicks to web pages while using the Services. It is your choice whether to accept or reject cookies/clear gifs and you can set your browser to reject cookies/clear gifs or to delete these cookies/clear gifs. However, if you choose to reject cookies/clear gifs or delete them, it may limit some of the functionalities available or affect your experience with the Services.

**Information Gathered Using Genieo Software**  
Genieo Software is a desktop application which automatically generates a personal start page with relevant content and ad-hock personalized news widgets. Unlike other start pages, Genieo Software doesn’t use predefined topics. Instead it auto generates a set of micro topics, based on the user’s areas of interest.

**  
Unless you choose to use Genieo Web Access Service (as set forth below), Genieo Software does not share or send out any information. Its entire mapping and profiling process is performed solely on the user side. Any information indexed by Genieo Software is locally stored in your personal computer and is not sent to Genieo or otherwise stored in Genieo’s servers.**

Notwithstanding the aforesaid, certain usage information, general categories of your areas of interest and information gathered from your use of the Genieo Software and Genieo Innovation’s third party suppliers’ search engine services may be stored on Genieo Innovation’s servers and subject to the terms of this Privacy Policy, transferred to Genieo Innovation’s third party suppliers.

During the installation of Genieo Software, browsers add-ons will be automatically installed in your Internet Explorer and Firefox browsers. Such add-ons serve as sensors that feed the Genieo Software with articles that you read and also assist your interface rendering. OnceGenieo Software is installed, you can always remove a browser add-on if you want. However, please note that if you choose to remove such add-ons, it may limit some of the functionalities available or affect your experience with Genieo Software.  
Once installed, Genieo Software continuously locally indexes and maps your web activities, such as favorite feeds, news and content, search history, cookies stored in your computer and other browsing history, in order to discover your personal fields of interest and needs, and to provide you with your personalized start page based on such profile.

Please note that information about your browsing history and web activities as aforesaid will be locally indexed and used, unless you specifically Opt-out to disable it or delete such files from your private computer. However, if you choose to disable Genieo Software from indexing as aforesaid, it may limit some of the functionalities available or affect your experience with Genieo Software.

Please also note that Genieo Software subscribes to Facebook’s RSS feeds (“Links” and “Notes” only) that are available to you while you are logged in to your Facebook account. This process is similar to the RSS subscription process that Genieo Software does in order to receive from third parties’ sources various RSS feeds published by them (as further described in the chapter _“Information from Other Sources”_ below). If you are not interested that Genieo Software will follow your Facebook’s RSS feeds as aforesaid, you can choose that it will not follow this feed from the application on Facebook.

Genieo Software may also subscribe to Twitter’s RSS feeds in order to filter and present items from your Twitter account, however this is subject to your explicit consent as you must permit Genieo Software to access your account (by entering your Twitter’s username and password), as required by Twitter for any third party application. If you are not interested that Genieo Software will follow your Twitter’s RSS feeds as aforesaid, you can choose that it will not follow this feed whether through your Twitter’s account directly or by clicking “Deny” on Twitter’s page, while accessing from Genieo Software.

Genieo Software respects your secured content and automatically disables itself once you navigate to secured sites. Accordingly, Genieo Software does not track or collect any information transferred on secured protocols (i.e. https, SSL), or any secured sites referring to bank accounts, credit card information, etc.

Genieo Software also disables itself once you navigate to sites that Genieo Innovation believe that are impropriate and/or that their content should not appear on a start page (e.g. pornographic sites).  
In addition, Genieo Software enables you to block it from mapping specific topics and/or feeds. From time to time, Genieo Software will notify you of specific topics and/or feeds – you can easily turn off such notifications by clicking “settings” and selecting “disable notifications”.

Please note that certain Non Personal Usage Information about your installation (e.g. type of operating system, version number of Genieo Software) will be sent to Genieo Innovation and/or Genieo Innovation third party suppliers and/or third parties’ web analytics services as aforesaid when you first install the Genieo Software, when Genieo Software automatically checks for updates and when you uninstall Genieo Software.

In addition, while you are using the Genieo Software, Genieo Innovation and/or Genieo Innovation third party suppliers and/or third parties’ web analytics services as aforesaid may collect further Non Personal Usage Information such as crash reports (including information from files, applications and servers that were running at the time of malfunction) and non-personal usage statistics (e.g. number of clicks on each link), in order to provide you personal contents, for example, personal news.

If you decide that you don’t want to use Genieo Software, you have several options:

  * You can temporary disable Genieo Software from the browser button menu. When you disable Genieo Software as aforesaid, your web activities will not be mapped and new content will not be offered. You can reactivate Genieo Software from the browser button menu.
  * You can remove the add-on from the browser that you are using.
  * You can fully uninstall Genieo Software at any time, by double clicking “add/remove programs” in you control panel. As the information indexed by Genieo Software is locally stored in your personal computer and is not shared and/or sent to Genieo Innovation and/or otherwise stored in Genieo Innovation’s servers, when uninstalling the Genieo Software, all the information indexed by the Genieo Software in your computer shall be immediately deleted.

For further information regarding Genieo Software, please contact: [support@genieo.com](mailto:support@genieo.com).

**Information from Other Sources**  
Genieo Innovation automatically collects information from multiple third parties’ sources to provide, inter alia, the users of Genieo Software with the most accurate personalized start page. By using the Genieo Software, you also agree to be automatically subscribed to receive from third parties’ sources various RSS feeds published by them.  
Please note that Genieo Software will automatically subscribe to third parties’ free sources, in order to use their RSS feeds, unless you specifically Opt-out to disable it. However, if you choose to disable Genieo Software from the aforesaid subscription, it may limit some of the functionalities available or affect your experience with Genieo Software.  
Genieo Innovation does not monitor, control, edit or manipulate any of the collected information and presents it “As-Is”. Genieo Innovation is not responsible for any of the information which is presented at these sources and does not control the disclosure of any information, which is made available by these sources. Genieo Innovation has no technological capability, legal right or ability to remove, edit, update, change or delete any information at the source.

**Genieo Web Access Services**  
Genieo Web Access Service enables the users of Genieo Software to synchronize and access their feeds, news and topics from different readers and mobile applications.

Please note that if you wish to use GenieoWeb Access Service, you will first have to actively perform the subscription process set forth below, and to provide your explicit consent.  
Please also note that in order to subscribe to Genieo Web Access Service, you must be a user of Genieo Software.

In order to subscribe and use Genieo Web Access Service, you must first have a personal account on Genieo’s servers (“Access Account”). This can be done in one of the following ways: (i) by providing an email and a password. Please note that in such case, you will be asked to verify your email by logging in to this email and activate your Access Account. Please also note that as part of the aforesaid process, you will be required to provide personally identifying information, including, but not limited to, first and last name, email address, password, country of origin and other identifying information as shall be required by Genieo. Following the completion of this process, any log in to Genieo Web Access Service will be made by using your username and password; or (ii) by using your Facebook/Google account in order to log in to Genieo Web Access Service, via Facebook/Google Connect service. Please note that in such case, at the first time you will be automatically referred to a Facebook webpage and will be asked to approve the use of your Facebook/Google account by Genieo Web Access Service. You will have to perform this process both from your private computer (to allow the synchronization from your private computer to Genieo’s servers), and from your mobile application (to allow the synchronization from Genieo’s servers to your mobile). Following the completion of this process, any log in to Genieo Web Access Service will be made through your Facebook/Google account. Please note that logging in to Genieo Web Access Service via your Facebook/Google account will technically enable Geneio to access your profile information, photos, your friends’ info and activities. However, Genieo does not and will not make any use of such information and will use your Facebook/Google account only for the sole purpose of allowing you to log in to Genieo Web Access Service using existing account (i.e. instead of creating a new account, providing again identifying information including new password etc.). 

Having such Access Account will enable the synchronization of the feeds, news and topics displayed on your personal start page via Genieo Software, from your personal computer to your Access Account. Once your Access Account is generated, synchronization will be performed automatically and constantly. Other then such feeds, news and topics, no other information displayed on your personal start page via Genieo Software will be synchronized. 

Upon synchronization as aforesaid, the last 50 items displayed on your start page will be available on your Access Account for web access, and you will be able to log on to the Access Account (whether by using your username and password, or via your Facebook/Google account as aforesaid), and view them via different mobile applications and readers. 

Please note that by subscribing to Genieo Web Access Service and creating an Access Account, you hereby agree that Genieo Software will send out and store your feeds, news and topics on Genieo’s servers.

If you decide that you don’t want to use Genieo Web Access Service, you can stop the synchronization at any time. In such event any of your content stored on Genieo’s servers will be deleted, and you will not be able to view it through the web. 

**Use of Usage Information**  
Genieo Innovation will provide the Services in full compliance with any applicable law. Genieo Innovation reserves the right to disclose any gathered information as required by law and when Genieo Innovation believes that such disclosure is necessary to protect its rights, the integrity of the Services, Genieo Innovation’s systems and technology, and/or to comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process served in connection with the Services.

**Information Security**  
Genieo Innovation is committed to protect the security of its users’ information and takes reasonable measures available to assure information security. However, no method of Internet transmission or electronic storage is 100% secure and Genieo Innovation cannot guarantee its absolute security. By using the Services, you expressly agree that Genieo Innovation will not be liable for any third party action, misuse, abuse or infringement of data and information security.

**Disclaimer Regarding Linked Sites**  
While using the Services, you may be linked from or to third parties sites. Genieo Innovation is not responsible for any information, content, terms of use of privacy policy at these sites. Genieo Innovation takes a careful notice in choosing its business partners and affiliates and aims to associate only with reliable partners which are committed to users’ privacy. However, remember that when you use a link to go from the website and/or Genieo Software to another website, this Genieo Innovation’s Privacy Policy is no longer in effect. By your browsing and interacting on any other website, including websites which have a link on Genieo Innovation’s website and/or Genieo Software, you are subject to that website’s own rules and policies. Please read over those rules and policies before proceeding.

**Ads**  
Ads appearing on Genieo Software may be delivered to users by advertising partners. The gathered information allows ad networks to, among other things, deliver targeted advertisements that they believe will be of most interest to you. This Privacy Policy does not cover the use by any advertisers.

**Feedback**  
Genieo Innovation may, from time to time, ask you to provide information regarding your experience while using the Services, for the purpose of measuring and improving the quality of the Services and the user’s experience. This feedback is very important to us, but you are not obligated to provide any information. However, any and all information that you voluntarily choose to provide us in feedback forms, and any survey that you may participate in, shall be used solely and anonymously for the purpose of reviewing the feedback and improving our Services.

**Assignment**  
Genieo Innovation is allowed, at its sole discretion, to assign this Privacy Policy or any rights hereunder to any third party, without giving prior notice. In any event of assignment as aforesaid, all the provisions of this Privacy Policy shall apply, _mutatis mutandis_.  
For any additional information regarding this Privacy Policy, please contact: [privacy@genieo.com](mailto:privacy@genieo.com).
